白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
I wonder if I should talk to Sachiko-sama about Touko-chan running away from home?
Yumi, Mass is starting.
Yes!
Bye! Have a good New Year!
Like this?
Yes. You can do it very neatly this way.
Good day!
What's going on, Shimako-san?
You're challenging yourself by making cakes!
Just a bit.
For some reason, I just wanted to make one.
Eh?
Rei-sama said she would teach me if I was going to do this.
That's right.
We can't eat Rei-sama's special cake next year.
Shimako-san wanted to continue what she did.
We're going to start feeling the approach of the graduation ceremony like this...
I'm sorry for being late!
Ah, Yumi-sama.
I apologize for this morning.
Nope. I'm sorry, too.
Noriko-chan, are you by yourself?
Kanako-san and Touko will be here soon.
They met Rosa Chinensis on their way here, so they left this to me.
I was told to carry this over here.
Ah, it's Youko-sama's writing!
She was the previous Rosa Chinensis, wasn't she?
Yes, she was.
Kanako and Touko are coming in a bit, right?
Then I'll go as well.
That Yoshino...
Yoshino is also going to use today's party as a chance to introduce her candidate for sisterhood to Rei.
Would you like help me put these up together?
Sure.
Sorry we're late.
Onee-sama!
Kanako-chan. Touko-chan!
Yumi-sama, thank you for inviting us today!
Good afternoon, everyone.
Thank you for the invitation again this year!
Sorry for being late.
Am I the last one?
I guess not. Yoshino-san isn't here.
Yoshino.
This way!
Sorry for the wait!
Um...
This is bad!
Rei-sama's nervous from having to meet Yoshino's candidate,
and Yoshino-san froze after seeing Rei-sama's nervousness!
That girl is Nana-san...
Do your best, Yoshino-san!
Then how about we take a group picture first?
Huh?
Can everyone please line up in two rows over there?
Just what I expected from you, Tsutako-san!
You changed the atmosphere!
Touko-chan, scoot in a bit more.
Sure.
Thanks.
Huh?
For coming even though you had plans.
But I didn't think it was like me to do this.
It is different from your usual character, isn't it?
I'm taking it now!
Okay! Thank you!
Then how about we start?
We'll decide the seating arrangement by drawing lots.
Drawing lots?
Yoshino-san looks crestfallen.
She couldn't sit next to Arima Nana.
I'm also separated from Touko-chan as well...
I really want to switch seats.
Let's start with a simple self-introduction and a report on how you've been doing.
It's been a while since we've all gathered like this, right Rei?
A self-introduction during something like this?
The last time was the school festival.
I see! It's for Arima Nana-san's sake!
Sounds fine.
Second year, pine class. Takeshima Tsutako.
I'm a member of the photography club.
To conclude my self-introduction, I'm hoping to become a photographer in the future.
I'll make it so no one will feel down.
I'm the Rosa Gigantea en bouton, Nijo Noriko.
My hobby is appreciating Buddhist statuary art.
I wanted to take a small trip to view some Buddhist statues after exams,
but I'm no longer able to.
I'm Rosa Foetida, Hasekura Rei.
I'm a member of the kendo club. However, we've only been truly busy this year.
I wonder if there anything else...
Ah, that's right.
Due to some unexpected events recently, I now have a boyfriend who's younger than me.
How old is he?
About ten?
Ten?!
Yumi-chan.
Touch!
TL Note: This is similar to the English word "tag".
Second year, pine class. Fukuzawa Yumi.
I'm the Rosa Chinensis en bouton.
Um...
During the break, I went to an amusement park with Onee-sama!
On the way back, we stopped by her house and I had a taste of her mother's delicious homemade mille-feuille.
It was delicious!
Middle school division third year, Arima Nana.
Thank you for inviting me.
Due to some unexpected events,
I came to know of Shimazu Yoshino-sama and I heard about the party.
I absolutely wanted to attend this.
Although I realize it's rude of me to have requested of such a thing,
I still would like to ask for everyone's guidance.
After that, Onee-sama talked about what happened at the amusement park.
Kanako-chan reported to us that she joined the basketball club.
Shimako-san talked about how she came to have an interest in making sweets.
And then finally...
First year, camellia class. Matsudaira Touko.
I'm a member of the drama club.
Is that it?
Young master, I'm fine.
Oh, you were providing for the needy in accordance with practice on this holy night, were you not?
Thank you very much.
Young master, what a kind person you are.
I got it! It's a small monologue!
There's nothing I can do about it.
My clothes are tattered, and I'm also always hungry.
Of course I would be mistaken for a pitiful child.
Was that okay, Kanako-san?
I had nothing particularly to mention, so that was a substitute.
Just in that small amount of time, she was able to grab everyone's attention.
Touko-chan really is amazing!
It has the same taste as Rei-sama's!
The Bûche de Noël that Rei-sama and Shimako-san made was really delicious.
TL Note: Bûche de Noël is known as a yule log in English.
Afterwards, it was free time.
We played games together and talked to each other. We passed the time happily.
If you're looking for Kanako-chan, she already left.
She said she was going to meet with her mother.
In order to maintain the joyful atmosphere, she said she would sneak out.
She didn't want Touko-chan to notice.
I'm not sure.
Is that so? Thank you very much.
Let's play the next game!
Noriko-chan, ready?
Noriko-chan, hurry!
Wait, Shimako-san!
Touko-chan?
She asked me if I was going to inherit my family's line of work.
Work?
We run a temple.
And then what did you say?
I said I didn't know, and then she asked me what would happen to the temple.
What would happen?
Who knows? It'd be nice if my brother would inherit it, though.
Shimako-san, you have an older brother?
Yes.
Touko-chan said the same thing, and then she seemed like she was contemplating something.
I wonder if something happened with Touko-chan's family.
Something probably did.
She won't come to me.
If it's you, Yumi-san, she'll listen to you.
Don't be too hasty.
Yeah...
Why am I the only one that doesn't know that about you, Rei-chan?!
What happened?
Yoshino-san brought Nana-san over to Rosa Foetida, and...
Rei-chan! Rei-chan!
Nana-san said that she wanted to meet you someday.
Okay. Bring her to my place during winter break.
We don't have to rush it.
How about when you visit in the spring to help the underclassmen?
TL Note: The school year ends and begins in the spring in Japan, so Rei will have already graduated by then.
I won't be coming.
But the Lilian Women's College is nearby.
I didn't send in my application for admissions.
What do you mean?
I'm not going to the college here.
Sachiko-sama, Rei-chan is....
Yoshino-chan, calm down.
Sachiko-sama, you knew.
Why didn't you tell me?!
Because you didn't ask.
Of course I wouldn't ask! You always told me you were going to Lilian!
You're right. I'm sorry.
Why are you going to a different university?
I want to study a subject that's not offered at Lilian.
What is it?
I'm thinking of studying physical education.
I don't know if I'll inherit it or not, but I want to stay involved with my family's dojo.
It's also useful to have knowledge of the body's functions and how it moves.
Most importantly, it's what I want to study.
I wish I could've heard that from you when we were alone.
If you had just told me straightforwardly, I wouldn't be so against it.
Sorry.
I wanted to know before anyone else did.
Onee-sama, what about you?
What do you plan to do after graduation?
I wanted to talk about this elsewhere, when it's just the two of us.
Sorry.
I'll be going to Lilian Women's College.
I see...
Huh?!
Is there something wrong with me being nearby?
Ah, no! That's not it!
Congratulations!
How silly. I submitted my application, but the results haven't come out yet.
I'm so relieved! I won't be separated from Onee-sama.
That's right! Before I forget, I have to give her my present.
Wait!
Leaving already?
Yes.
You said it was fine if I left in the middle of it.
I wasn't even aware that Kanako-chan left already.
Why are you coming with me?
I just felt like walking with you for a bit.
Without being considerate of how I feel?
Am I a bother?
No.
Did you really only feel like walking?
I thought you might want to talk about something.
Ah, something to talk about.
Yeah, let's talk.
Rei-sama's decision was surprising, wasn't it?
She's going to a different university.
Sachiko-sama will be staying here at Lilian,
so you're happy, aren't you, Yumi-sama?
Well, basically, third years are all facing the dreams they have for themselves and heading straight for them, or something like that.
No one can achieve the same future that they've framed in their mind.
Eh?
Touko-chan?
When we were in primary school, we were given a blank map during social studies.
At the time, I became really excited.
"I'll draw mountains and cities here.
A perfect map that looks almost printed, and wouldn't lose to anything else."
But then I realized,
it's not that easy to do.
The page that I had drawn was completely different from what I had imagined.
Even a single blank atlas can't go that well.
It's the same with life.
I had my eyes opened.
If you can't make a perfect map, it would've been better to just make the map a wet mess of pink flowers and water dots!
If I did that, I might have made a beautiful map for myself.
But...
I couldn't do it.
Touko-chan...
I've been ranting.
Please forget what I said.
Touko-chan!
Will you...
become my sister?
Am I not good enough?
Yumi-sama...
"Thank you very much.
Yumi-sama, what a kind person you are.
Just joking."
And if I said that?
I'm not a good girl like the one in the monologue.
If this is charity for the sake of this holy night, go somewhere else.
Touko-chan-
Anyway, I cannot accept your rosary.
Excuse me.
Yumi.
Onee-sama!
I thought that if I waited here, we could be alone.
It's a handkerchief, isn't it?
Open it and see.
Don't think that it's as poorly made as last year's.
I've improved this year.
Roses. Red roses.
Thank you very much!
That's right, me too!
Oh my...
A book cover.
This is a rose, isn't it?
We were thinking of the same thing.
Thank you.
I'll use it during both winter and summer.
It's hot during summer.
What's wrong?
Onee-sama, I...
Did something happen with Touko-chan?
She didn't accept my rosary.
I see...
Touko-chan isn't the only first year.
But...
You're right.
Then you just can't give up!
When Shimako refused me, I thought that it didn't have to be Shimako.
But it was different from when you rejected me, Yumi.
Even if I would be too stubborn, I wanted you to accept my rosary.
Having your rosary refused isn't the end of the world.
Be more confident.
Yes.
But, it's painful, isn't it?
Um...
Then, is it alright if I cry a bit?
Yes.
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
My parents mentioned annulling the engagement between Suguru-san and I during this New Year.
It's fine, right? Both of you are still young, after all.
But weren't you going to make us marry, and then entrust the Ogasawara group to us?
Oh? The reason we had the two of you get engaged was because you had said that you wanted to be Suguru-san's wife when you were a child.
That determination to jump off the platform at Kiyomizu was easily destroyed.
TL Note: Kiyomizu Temple is a temple in Kyoto that is very famous for its incredibly high platform. This is just a reference to having the "courage" to jump off the platform.
Next time, The Other Side of the Clouded Glass.
New Years actually had a story like this.