白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
Will you...
be my sister?
Yumi-sama...
"Thank you very much.
Yumi-sama, what a kind person you are."
Just kidding.
And if I said that?
Touko-chan didn't accept my rosary.
I told everything to Onee-sama.
Having your rosary refused isn't the end of the world.
Be more confident.
Yes.
But it's painful, isn't it?
Um...
Then, is it alright if I cry a bit?
Here.
Sorry for making everyone worry.
What had happened isn't that big of a deal.
Touko-chan rejected Yumi's rosary when she offered it to her.
That's all.
No way!
Noriko,
watch your words.
Ah, sorry.
I wasn't saying Rosa Chinensis was lying!
I know.
But this is the truth.
It's probably not something worth telling others,
since this makes everyone worry.
In addition, there's something I want to request from everyone.
A request?
I don't want any of you to become involved with what's going on between Yumi and Touko-chan.
Please just watch over Yumi from a distance,
rather than becoming involved by pitying her or hating Touko-chan.
This is their problem.
Of course, I'll be doing the same.
Onee-sama...
Since Sachiko, the older sister, is asking us to do this,
we're in no position to interfere. All right?
Yumi-san, you haven't given up yet, have you?
It's cold.
Why?
Touko-chan's been hurt much more than me all this time.
That's how I feel.
A few days later...
Onee-sama!
A New Year's party at Sachiko-sama's house!
And only girls are allowed.
Onee-sama, thank you for the invitation!
You'll come?
If you'll have me, of course!
I've already received permission from my parents,
and I've gotten confirmation from Yoshino-san and Shimako-san through the phone.
That's great.
Yumi.
Yes?
I invited Touko as well.
I see.
It was my idea.
Sorry for not giving you a chance to refuse.
No, it's all right.
She might not come.
I know.
Even then, I thought it was a good idea.
I feel that Touko-chan will just get further and further away if you don't do anything.
You're right.
Are you mad at me?
Even though I told everyone to just watch over you,
I immediately started being meddlesome.
Are you an esper? You read my mind.
I'm not.
But I'm your Onee-sama.
And that's all I need to be.
You're right.
I'm off!
I wonder if Saeko obaa-sama will be happy?
TL Note: Obaa-sama is a term used for women of middle-age or older.
Good day to you, Yumi-sama.
Noriko-chan!
Happy New Year.
Yes, Happy New Year!
Yumi-sama, um...
What's wrong?
I feel like I have to apologize to you.
I wanted to apologize and never bring it up again, but...
Is this about Touko-chan?
I've always thought that it would be great if Touko became your sister.
No, that it would be great if you would be willing to become Touko's sister.
But I thought that you didn't think much of Touko.
So that's why I was so sad when you tried to take care of Touko with such simple intentions.
I'm sorry.
I see.
You were thinking very seriously about Touko, weren't you?
Even then...
Turning down someone's proposal for sisterhood is neither right nor wrong.
But I definitely don't think that lying to yourself is a good thing either!
Noriko-chan, you think Touko-chan doesn't hate me?
Yes.
Then I must've been the one that made a mistake.
A mistake?
Yeah.
About the time, the place, or even her feelings.
Maybe even the way I said it.
Sorry! Did you guys wait long?
Nope. We got here early.
Happy New Year!
Could this be is your first time being together for the New Year!?
Yes.
Is there a problem?
Sorry! I didn't notice!
I'll go somewhere else, so please take your time.
What are you being so considerate for?
But...
Um, what about Rei-sama and Yoshino-sama?
Those two said they would go there directly.
Then how about we head over there now?
We're here.
Is this a park!?
Welcome.
Happy New Year!
Come in.
Rei and the others are already here.
Okay!
Please excuse the intrusion!
Anything else?
Um, let's see...
Yoshino-san! Rei-sama!
Oh, Happy New Year.
Happy New Year!
Sayako oba-sama, Yumi and the others have arrived!
Welcome.
Thanks for coming.
Yumi-chan, you remembered, didn't you?
I'm so impressed!
Now then. Please take care of each other this year as well.
Please take care of me!
It's a good non-alcoholic drink, isn't it?
It is.
You're eating the ozouni already?
TL Note: Ozouni is a traditional type of soup often eaten with mochi at New Years.
It's okay, right?
I'm hungry from helping out!
Thanks for the meal!
It certainly does look good.
Right?
Rei-chan made the stock!
I wonder what's going on with Touko-chan right now.
That must be someone from the sushi shop.
They're always on time.
There's no way she'd come...
I'm going to start reading them.
TL Note: The game they're playing is called "utagaruta." One person reads the first few lines of a poem,
"Lying all alone,
Through the hours of the night, till the daylight comes:"
and the two teams of players compete to pick out the correct name of the poem. This style of playing is specifically known as "genpei gassen".
There!
Here.
"The Mother of Michitsuna."
You're correct, Shimako-chan.
On to the next one then.
"Eight-fold cherry flowers"
Eight-fold cherry flowers...
Cherry flowers...
"That at Nara--ancient seat"
Found it.
"Lady Ise no Osuke."
That's the right one!
Now, the next one.
You're amazing, Shimako-chan!
Really. She's as good as you, Sachiko.
You did better than last year, didn't you?
I couldn't get any...
Yes.
There's a lot of poems about what people brooded over.
Like their troubles.
Aren't there one hundred different troubles?
TL Note: The game takes its poems from the Ogura Hyakunin Isshu, a collection of 100 poems by 100 different poets.
I wonder.
But if that's how it is,
people who can grab so many cards will mix up human emotions,
and become confused, won't they?
Really, Onee-sama.
All right.
Next is Human Snakes and Ladders.
Human Snakes and Ladders?
Yes!
Let's play this by competing as pairs.
How about grouping up according to the colors of the roses?
Oh...
Instead of using pieces, you yourselves will be moving around.
Each room in the house has a different name,
so please follow the directions in each room.
Now, let's begin!
Alright!
Go!
Three.
Three is the Water Flea Room.
Water Flea Room?
Sachiko-san has an advantage when it comes to the rooms on the second floor, right?
That's the reason.
You even thought that far ahead?
Let's go, Yoshino!
Okay!
There!
Five is the Hippopotamus Room.
Let's go.
Okay!
Here goes!
You two are going to Furisode Fish Room. Have fun.
TL Note: Furisode is a type of kimono.
The Messy Room...
This isn't the right place either.
Where's the room!?
The Ostrich Room...
The number of squares on the board and the distance between rooms have no relationship, do they?
There it is, Onee-sama!
The Kimono Room!
What are we supposed to do?
Yumi, take off your clothes.
No matter how you think about it, the rule here is to put on one of the kimonos.
B-But...
There's no time to waste!
But I don't have to be the one to change!
Don't be silly!
It's the younger sister's job to do these kinds of things, isn't it?
Plus, it's not interesting if I change, since it'll only be a difference in color!
Now, accept it and strip!
W-W-W... Wait, Onee-sama!
Close the door at least!
There's only women in the house!
Oh...
Sign: Make the younger sister wear a kimono
Yumi-chan, you're cute!
Really, it suits you!
Thanks.
All teams cleared their first tasks.
Let's continue!
Even though I continued to experience the constricting feeling of the kimono's sash,
the two of us managed to complete all of the tasks given to us.
We, the Rosa Chinensis team, won.
Congratulations!
Jeez! Even though we tried so hard!
Aren't you glad you came?
Yes. Although, you didn't know if anyone had anything else planned today or not,
you still managed to gather everyone together.
This was to cheer me up.
You really do understand.
That's great!
I also understand that you're the one who created this chance.
I'll hold what you've done for me close to my heart.
How silly. You don't have to say that much.
I'm a friend, after all.
Yumi-san, Saeko obaa-sama says she'll make some matcha later!
TL Note: Matcha is the traditional type of tea made and drank in tea ceremonies.
Hurry and help us clean up!
Give me the trash!
This is fun.
This is fun!
It's delicious.
I feel so happy!
But...
For some reason, I feel like a cold wind is creeping into my heart.
That's probably because your emotions are locked in a different room in your heart.
Did I say something?
Yes.
Something like you were happy, but a cold wind is flowing into your heart.
There's something wrong with me.
Even though two of you are here, I'm mumbling strange things to myself...
You can't help it!
Even if the rooms with your feelings for your Onee-sama or friends are full,
if any of the other rooms in your heart is empty,
you feel like you're missing something.
Another room?
Your younger sister's room.
There's no such room!
Up until now.
But you recently added the extra room for Touko's sake, right?
Even though you already made a room for her, there's no sister to live in there,
so you have a hole in your heart right now, Yumi-san.
Like I said, it's obvious!
That's what's wrong. Don't worry too much about it!
You said it well.
Shimako-san.
I'm speaking from past experience.
I'm also in the process of adding an extra room, okay?
I see...
A person's heart is like a house, huh?
If I think of it that way, it's easy to understand.
And the room shared by Onee-sama and I is already overloading.
Okay! Just as I thought, we really should write before going to bed.
Write what?
Nakakiyo.
Let's sleep after we write palindromes starting with "nakakiyo" and put them under our pillows.
It's a charm for having a good first dream of the new year.
You remembered well, Yumi.
Now, I'm going to turn off the lights.
Good night!
What a sweet expression.
I can feel this much just from looking at my friend's sister.
If this was my own sister...
My first dream of the new year was about her. Touko-chan.
Touko-chan was there, near my room.
But between us was a pane of clouded glass.
I wanted to see Touko-chan's face.
Please, Touko-chan! Wipe the glass from your side too!
If you don't, the glass won't clear up!
Yumi-san, what're you doing?
Oh, nothing really.
There must be some kind of mistake.
How can I make her understand me?
Touko-chan, please!
Look over here!
Touko-chan...
Thank you very much for the invitation.
It was a lot of fun.
Please come again.
Have a good day.
A good day to you too!
I want to see Touko-chan.
I want to make her my sister.
I want to know everything about her.
Maybe I should go to Kashiwagi-san's place.
If I ask Kashiwagi-san, I might be able to learn more about Touko-chan.
But...
Touko-chan might not be happy about that.
Instead, she might close her heart to me.
I can't do that.
That's not something an older sister would do.
I'm not qualified to be an older sister.
The third semester started before I could do anything.
Touko-chan...
I'm pleased to see you, Yumi-sama.
M-Me too!
Touko-chan was smiling.
As if nothing happened between us last year.
As if there was nothing between us at all.
As if she had forgotten everything on purpose.
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
Rei-chan, you can't tell anyone!
I know.
When I was learning to ride a bike, that's what Rei-chan said to me.
But in a moment with extraordinarily bad timing, things got out of hand.
That was winter.
It was after Nana and Rei-chan had their competition.
Yoshino, you cheered for Rei-chan, didn't you?
"That's all right" was what Rei said.
Next time: The Masked Actress.
Yumi-san, you're experiencing painful feelings different from mine, aren't you?
Gokigenyou.