The maidens that have gathered in Maria-sama's garden...
pass through the tall gate once again today, carrying the pure visage of angels.
A deep colored sailor uniform envelopes their mind and bodies, which has no impurities.
Keeping the pleats on one's skirt unruffled.
Keeping the collar of the sailor uniform neat and tidy.
Walking slowly is preferred here.
Private Lilian Girls Academy.
This is the garden of maidens.
白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
There's only five minutes left!
W-What should we do?
At this rate, soon the chance will be given to the absentee's to guess!
Yumi.
Y-Yes?
Please stand up.
I'm sorry?
It's okay. Please stand up.
Yumi-sama!
Touko-chan!
Yumi-sama, please forgive me for how rude I've been until now!
In addition to that,
would you please...
make me your sister?!
It is now 4:40.
Because the time allowed is now over,
those of you who've participated in the treasure hunt,
please assemble at the inner garden.
Um... Everyone, we should hurry outside...
I just have to take it with me, right?
Wait a second.
I want to confirm one thing.
What will be done with the red card?
Er... Uh...
It's Touko-chan's, isn't it?
But, Rosa Chinensis...
I have no exclusive right to it.
I certainly did tell Yumi to stand up,
but the one who actually made Yumi stand up was Touko-chan.
Then please give the red card to Matsudaira-san.
Yes.
Touko-chan.
Here are the results!
As planned, after the hour for searching had passed,
Mami-san revealed the locations of the cards.
Shimako's white card was hidden underneath one of the teacher's cars,
and in the end, since no one had found her card,
the winner will be the absentee who guessed the location of her card correctly.
The yellow card was found for the second time in a row by Tanuma Chisato-san,
and Touko-chan became the winner of the red card.
We personally handed out bite-sized chocolates to...
Thanks for participating.
the participants who were unable to find the cards.
Here you go.
Thus, the Valentine's Day event,
the treasure hunt for the next Roses' cards,
ended safely, but...
By the way, what happened?
What do you mean?
What happened after that?
Touko-chan?
Yes. Did you two talk about plans or called each other for the date?
There weren't any new developments.
Oh...
Hold on.
I'll run over, and bring Touko-chan here!
Wai-
And if I get involved with this, things will become more complicated...
Yeah...
Um, Touko seems to have come to school, but she wasn't in class today.
It caused quite a stir,
and even I was cornered by people.
It's become quite a big rumor.
Yes.
Maybe it's better if I hurry and hand her the rosary, and formally make her my sister.
We finally meet!
Good afternoon.
I've been looking for you, Touko-chan!
After taking a peek at the Drama club practicing in the gymnasium, I thought you'd be here.
This is about the date, isn't it? The date from the Valentine's Day event.
Yes. Well...
How does Sunday two weeks from now sound?
That day is fine.
Do you want to go anywhere?
Is it all right if I pick the place?
Of course! It just has to stay within the budget of our day trip.
Here. The details of the trip.
The budget is two thousand yen per person.
Considering the cost of eating lunch, we won't be able to go too far.
But if we go to somewhere that's regular for students, we can get some lunch.
You're right!
I have to tell her directly.
Touko-chan!
Ah, I'm sorry. The two of you were in the middle of something.
It must be cold.
If you would like, please come inside.
No, thank you. Sorry for disturbing your club's practice.
I'll be leaving soon, so...
I see.
But you don't have to be that courteous!
It's just the two of us, after all.
See you then...
Um... Yumi-sama?
What is it?
Can you give me a reply after the date?
Good morning.
This is great.
Huh?
You told me that this would be a mystery tour, so you didn't tell me anything about today's date!
I was really troubled trying to decide what to wear.
Then, let's go.
First, we'll take the bus.
We took the bus,
and arrived at a private train line.
We took a train from there, and went to a different place.
Here.
Thanks.
The mystery tour that Touko-chan planned...
took us farther and farther from Tokyo.
But up until now, Touko-chan has been rather silent.
My grandfather was incredibly overjoyed when he heard that I would inherit the hospital.
Huh?
This happened a long time ago...
Hospital? Your grandfather's hospital, right?
Yes, from my father's side.
But my father is a single child, and he isn't a doctor.
So then, you...
It's a small hospital, but it's loved by the locals and the patients alike.
That's why I didn't want it to be closed down.
But my grandfather will be retiring in three years.
Then, what's going to happen to the hospital?
Right now, it's being taken care of by a husband and wife pair that had helped my grandfather.
No one took me inheriting the hospital seriously.
In three years, I would have only just graduated from high school.
I'm nowhere near obtaining a medical license.
I thought of marrying a doctor, but my parents were against it.
They said it was foolish to marry just for the hospital.
I thought that I wasn't needed anymore.
Since someone capable will be found, I had no business in getting involved.
So...
I ran away from home.
Then that day...
Yes.
Sorry. I don't quite understand.
Why are you so determined to inherit the hospital?
Do you not understand?
You can't trust the people who've come to take care of things?
No, I can. They're very good people.
Then, why?
For me, becoming a Matsudaira is more important than life itself.
Why?
I'm slowly getting closer to Touko-chan.
Touko-chan's heart must lie at the destination of this trip.
Yumi-sama!
This way!
It's a bus for carrying patients.
My grandfather's hospital is far from the station.
Come on, take off your shoes!
The bus from the station left the town, and entered a rural area.
It's almost noon.
Minus the money for the transportation back, we only have about six hundred yen between the two of us.
Maybe there's a convenience store near the hospital?
Are you hungry?
Uh, no! Um-
Please wait little bit more.
Really, what am I thinking at a time like this?
My mother's in this picture.
This person?
Yes, that's her.
This is my mother.
It's delicious!
Thank goodness. It suits your taste.
I get it! The hospital's cafeteria!
We can eat within the budget here.
Oh, Touko.
Grandfather!
I heard you were coming, but I had a house call.
You look healthy.
I heard you caused some trouble for your parents when you ran away from home!
That's quite grown up of you.
Really, that happened last year, grandfather.
This is my grandfather.
This is an upperclassman from my school, Fukuzawa Yumi-sama.
Pleased to meet you!
Yumi-san, you said? Are you Sachiko-san's...
Do you know her?
Yes, Saiko-san speaks of her often.
Sachiko-sama's mother does?
I see... So you're Yumi-san, huh?
Please take care of Touko!
Don't take your eyes off of her for even one second!
I won't!
Oh, doctor.
Hello, Hashimoto-san.
In the end, I was too young.
What do you mean?
Noriko told me the same thing.
"Because it's been there since you were young, you can't see the big picture."
Oh, young lady.
Good afternoon.
You're here to visit?
Please enjoy your stay.
Thank you very much.
So you come here sometimes.
Yes.
How cute...
How about we go?
Sixteen years ago, there was an accident.
On a gentle, descending curved road,
a truck was forced into the opposite lane,
and crashed into a passenger car.
The passenger car had a young husband and wife riding in it, they died due to the crash.
I don't know the exact location, but it must have been around here.
A child that had just been born had been asleep in the child seat of the car, but the child was the only one that was saved without harm.
Just like the baby just now-
No, it was approximately one month after I was born, so I was even younger when it happened.
The lone baby that had been saved.
That was me.
I...
lost my parents once-
It's okay!
No, please listen!
I lost my parents,
and my only relative was my grandmother on my father's side.
My grandmother was also hospitalized here.
She couldn't raise me at all, so I was placed in an orphanage.
But all of a sudden, the Matsudaira's adopted me and raised me.
My adopted mother is this person,
and this person...
This person's the one who gave birth to me.
Then...
It's a coincidence.
The two of them were classmates in high school.
I just found that out recently.
But I knew from a long time ago that I wasn't the Matsudaira's daughter.
I overheard the talk of unsympathetic adults.
And so I thought:
If they had any bit of wisdom, they could find out by looking at the family register.
My birth mother had apparently performed plays with a small theater troop.
When I knew that, I thought about dropping drama.
But if I suddenly quit, my parents might get the wrong idea.
I love my current parents.
But I hurt them.
I cried when our opinions didn't match each other's when it came to the hospital.
I thought I wasn't needed anymore.
Up until that point, my parents hadn't taken any interest in what I knew.
Why are you telling me this?
I wanted you to know everything about me, Yumi-sama!
This is the secret that Kashiwagi-san had talked about.
I hated you, Yumi-sama.
You were bright, innocent, and had everything.
And you looked like you were never affected by anything.
Well, I get as confused as anyone else.
I understand that now.
Oh, really?
I wanted to become like you.
But I couldn't.
I even thought that I shouldn't be near you anymore.
But you steadily broke down the wall I had so desperately tried to make.
Can you not talk about others as if they're monsters?
It's true!
At the time, the rumor that I was a candidate to become your sister was spreading, too.
All I did was make you hate me.
There was no way I could become your sister.
I denied it frantically in my heart,
but, on the contrary, you were looking out for me.
That's why I ran...
Even then, you suddenly asked me: "Will you become my sister?"
Sorry...
She could have just released all of the one-sided emotions she had collected inside herself fully.
I'll listen to any number of complaints.
After all, we'll become sisters.
After feeling refreshed from spilling everything,
I'll fill an open part of her heart with happy memories.
Just like how I did with Sachiko-sama.
Please wait just a bit more.
Tomorrow, we'll go to school, and then...
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
Gokigenyou.