白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
The three of us second years were safely elected to the student council
despite being in an election with Touko-chan.
Yumi-san!
Yumi-sama.
I was looking at Touko the moment the results were released.
And then...
And then I knew.
Touko's purpose was to lose!
I knew it!
Touko-chan!
Congratulations, Rosa Foetida en bouton! How do you feel?
Thank you. I plan to do my best to not let down the expectations others have of me.
Congratulations, Yumi-sama!
Please do your best!
Thanks!
But why did she...
I see. Noriko-chan, you don't know either.
That's means you...
Wait, where are you going?
I'm going to ask her in person.
How about you come with me, Yumi-sama?
Erm...
I'm not going.
Why not?
I wonder.
I don't quite know why, but I don't need to.
You don't need to?
You don't want to know her reasons?
How should I put this? That doesn't really matter.
Do you plan to toss her aside?
Does it seem that way?
Yes.
It's the opposite, though.
The opposite?
Yes.
Sorry for disturbing you two.
Yumi-san, apparently the newspaper wants a comment from you.
Tsutako-san said she wants to take a commemorative photo of the three of us afterwards.
"I'm not tossing her aside."
Okay. Will do.
That's certainly what she said.
Noriko, you come too.
What? I'm...
Noriko-chan, it's all right if you don't come.
Let's meet up at the Rose Mansion.
All right...
Let's go, Yumi-san.
Okay.
I still feel a bit insecure.
But...
if I accept Yumi-sama's words, Touko might be able to be saved
Chinese food for dinner!
Doesn't that sound delicious?
What if one of us had lost?
We'd have a party to cheer you guys up, or a party to make Yoshino happy.
We'd just change the name of the party.
I see.
I'll admit, I was quite nervous.
Yumi-sama, what are you planning to do about Touko?
Why are you leaving her alone?
I don't understand.
There must be something...
Noriko?
Her smile...
didn't mean anything like "What's wrong?" or "It's all right." or even "Leave it to me."
But it was a smile that contained a combination of those.
Yumi-sama suddenly feels distant somehow.
Yumi wasn't even able to get the "to" from Touko out of her mouth.
She must have been chasing after Touko that time.
When she returned, her expression was clearly different.
What exactly happened?
There's something wrong with me too.
Oh really?
Yes!
Welcome back.
Welcome back, Sa-chan.
I'm back.
I should welcome you back too.
I heard about it.
You sprained your ankle while skiing?
Well, it's true.
Sachiko-san, Suguru-san brought back some rice cakes as a souvenir from his skiing trip.
Let's have some right now.
Hold on. I need to use the restroom.
Ah, me too.
Those two are good kids.
What happened while I was gone?
Why?
Yumi-chan and Touko.
Yumi and Touko-chan?
Are you concerned?
On the twelfth, Touko had an argument with her parents and ran away from home.
For half a day.
No one told me.
I didn't really want to make a big deal out of it, so I kept it quiet.
I see.
So is there some kind of relationship between Touko running away and Yumi?
I found Touko at Yumi's house.
At Yumi's house?
She didn't visit her because she was someone to depend on.
She met Yuuki close to where Yumi's house is.
Well, that's what I was told.
When was this?
I told you it was on the twelfth.
I know it was on the twelfth.
What I'm asking is whether it was before or after Christmas.
It was before.
If I remember correctly, it was in the week of their break.
I see.
This happened before Touko refused Yumi's rosary.
Yumi was worried about Touko.
She probably was.
Does your sudden spark of interest mean that
something happened between Touko and Yumi-chan?
Suguru-san, you're Touko's cousin after all.
You're concerned about your own family.
Yeah.
You're right.
But still, something like that happened between Yumi and Touko-chan.
This is their problem.
Even if I'm Yumi's older sister, I can't get involved.
I haven't answered your question if something happened or not
while you were gone, have I?
Yeah.
Touko-chan ran as a candidate for the student council and lost.
What?
I have no idea why she choose to do so.
Unbelievable.
Even though Yumi-chan was so...
Suguru-san, do you like Yumi?
Why are you saying something so strange?
I just-
You're right. I'm sorry.
I see.
I should have just laughed and said
"I love Yumi-chan because she's a nice girl."
You should have.
But I don't want to be misunderstood.
I don't know how I would've felt in the past,
but I've come to understand a few things now.
In terms of mass, my love for you is much greater than my love for Yumi.
It's a different kind of love, isn't it?
Yes.
You're just as smart as ever, Sa-chan.
Who are you comparing me to?
I'm not telling.
We should go back soon.
If we stay in here for too long, auntie will start to think strange things.
Wait a bit.
You forgot to wash your hands.
Just what you expect from cousins.
They're both so fastidious.
Here are the plans for this year's Valentine's Day.
This year, we'll be having another Valentine's Day event,
so we would like to ask for the cooperation of the Yamayuri Council,
of which Rosa Chinensis and Rosa Foetida have already agreed.
What?
What are you so surprised about?
But...
There's no reason to turn them down, is there?
Even so-
Please look at the handouts in front of you.
Hold on a second, Mami-san!
Isn't this the same thing as last year?
Exactly!
Of course, even if it's the same event, we'll be powering it up this year!
Last year, Rosa Chinensis' card was the only one that wasn't found within the time limit, correct?
Yes.
It's just too unfortunate to never have your card found, even though you went to the trouble of hiding it.
This year, in order to avoid that, we're planning to have a way in which the losers can play again.
How? Specifically.
We're planning to give a chance to those who cannot attend on that day.
A chance for those who can't participate?
That sounds good.
Up until the day before the event, we'll have people write down the areas where they think a card could be hidden,
and put it into a box.
Of course, the box won't be opened until the event starts,
so there's no way that the location of the cards can change.
If a card isn't found, then the person who guesses the correct location will be given the card.
Exactly.
And if no one guesses the correct location of a card?
The plan is to have the winner be the person who guesses the closest location,
but how about we plan out the details little by little by including everyone's opinion?
Now, if there are any questions...
Here!
About the event logistics written here...
It says: The boutons that will become Roses will be mingling with normal students.
Crap. I forgot to fix that.
I see.
You used the plan from last year to format this plan, didn't you?
I read that part, but I ignored it.
I was careless.
Shimako-san you're going to be a Rose again next year, and Noriko-chan is your bouton, right?
So which one of you is participating?
Of course, it's...
Noriko.
Onee-sama.
But Noriko, you're a bouton!
But won't you be Rosa Gigantea next year?
Even then, it clearly says "bouton" here.
It also says "Rose."
U-Um...
I'm very sorry.
This may sound irresponsible coming from the one who caused the confusion,
but what is everyone else's opinion?
Our opinion...
But I did it last year, so...
That kind of logic won't work.
If we accept your reasoning now, Shimako,
Noriko-chan can do the same thing next year.
But there's no guarantee that Noriko will become the next Rosa Gigantea after the election next year.
Then let me say this:
Isn't it odd in the first place to have someone take that kind of position in the event?
Shimako, why don't you participate?
Does it matter if you do it two years in a row?
Shimako, you have a lot of fans.
What's wrong? Let's do this together.
Or is there a reason why you wouldn't be able to do it?
It's not that I don't want to hide my card.
It's just...
It's just?
I just want to find the card that Noriko hides.
What?!
Me too.
I heard about last year's event from my classmates Atsuko-san and Miyuki-san,
and I thought, "I want to look for Onee-sama's card."
But just as I was about to give up because I'm a bouton this year,
we started talking about either the bouton or next year's Rose participates, so...
I thought this was a chance.
Noriko.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
Shimako, are you worried about who'll be the Rosa Gigantea after you?
No. I believe that Noriko will legitimately succeed me.
Then show her the side of you that's cooperative.
Since it'll be something she'll have to do next year.
I understand.
Onee-sama...
It's all right.
I'm going to make some tea.
Mami-san, if you're doing this again this year, does that mean you plan to do it again next year?
Of course! It's a popular event, after all.
Everyone's so happy.
Shimako-san has it good, hasn't she?
If we didn't have to see our Onee-sama off, we could immediately focus on our younger sisters.
That's true.
Hey...
Yumi-san, aren't you angry that our Onee-sama agreed to this without asking us?
Just a little bit.
Is that all?
Yeah...
Although it's a problem, I also don't think there's a reason to refuse just like Onee-sama said.
Last year, Mizuno Youko-sama had her dream fulfilled.
She wanted the Rose Mansion to be a place where elegance would always remain.
I want to see another dream like that.
Nana-chan will be applying.
Yoshino-san? You're spilling the tea leaves.
Yumi-san, you're calm, aren't you? How?
What do you mean?
I'm not quite sure, but you're very calm.
If you aren't sure, I have no idea.
Aside from Nana and myself, what do you plan to do about Touko-chan?
What I plan to do?
There's nothing I can do.
You're not going to make her your soeur?
She has to agree to it first, doesn't she?
That's true, but...
If I seem calm, maybe it's...
because there's no reason for me to rush things.
No need to rush?
Yeah.
Things like "I have to find a sister before Onee-sama graduates!" or
"I have to make Touko-chan my sister!"
Strangely, it's like I've lost any impatience I once had.
Was there any cause for it?
I don't know if there was any specific cause, but if I had to say it, it was the election.
The election?
Yeah.
Ever since, I've been thinking about how I want my relationship with Touko-chan to be.
I've been satisfied with that.
Even if I act hastily, the answer won't reveal itself, right?
Yumi-san, don't become an adult by yourself.
Eh? I'm not one at all!
Don't leave me behind!
What are you worried about? You're weird.
And then, they chased after Yumi-san, and it became a game of tag!
But...
After diligently reporting the whole thing, the Lilian newspaper became really popular!
According to rumor, it not only swept the high school division, but the middle school division too!
Oh right! I thought of something good!
But it might be a bit difficult.
If you can make it happen, you'll definitely...
What're you-
No, there's nothing for you to lose!
Hey, Mami-san!
Huh?
Will you allow students from the middle school division to participate this year?
Wait, Yumi-san!
Last year, some sneaked in to take a look, didn't they?
Eh? Yeah, I certainly heard something like that.
Got it. I'll ask the teachers.
Thanks, Mami-san!
Really, Yumi-san...
I told you not to leave me behind, didn't I?
Yoshino-san!
Ah, Mami-san.
Actually, this is about allowing the middle schoolers to participate.
Well, in terms of results, we managed to gain the teachers' approval through a compromise.
Compromise?
They're allowed to participate only through the guessing portion.
I see.
And that's how it is. So what are you going to do, Yoshino-san?
Are you going to tell Nana-chan right away?
I'll wait a bit.
Oh?
There's nothing to be hasty about.
Plus, even though everyone's different, the same thing might be affecting us all.
What is?
Soeurs.
Shimako-san!
Going to the Rose Mansion?
Yes.
Hold on a bit.
Thanks for the help.
Oh, good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
You're always so helpful.
Right now, the only ones here are Yumi-sama and I.
I should...
Actually, I have something to talk to you about, Noriko-chan.
What?
Of course, I wouldn't mind if Shimako-san or Yoshino-san were to come in and overhear us.
Is that so?
What's wrong?
Nothing. Excuse me.
What? Did you think it would be about Touko-chan?
Yes.
Nothing's really happened, so I don't really have anything to talk about.
I see.
But if there's anything you want to ask me, go ahead.
I don't know if I can give you a satisfying answer though.
Something I want to ask...
Something I want to ask Yumi-sama right now?
Why do you leave Touko alone?
Can I trust you when you say that you won't toss her aside?
What do you think of Touko losing the election?
Do you think you'll feel like handing Touko your rosary a second time?
Touko...
Do you like her?
I do.
I love her.
Then that's fine.
The proposal to allow middle schoolers to participate in the event that Yumi-san proposed was accepted,
but there were actually a number of students that had an illegal head start last time.
Since the teachers from the middle school division caught them,
they're discussing how to crack down on this for this year's event.
Yumi-sama likes Touko.
That was the one thing I wanted to hear most from her.
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
Mama sometimes sees bad dreams.
While she has nightmares, she calls out with a strained voice.
Although I came running to her, I was scolded and told not to go anywhere.
The reason Mama sees such dreams is because of a baby she lost.
But I pretend not to notice.
I don't want to lose my precious family.
Next time: Keyhole to the Heart.
When can the door to the heart be opened?
Gokigenyou