白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
The opening ceremony began.
Good morning, Yumi-sama.
G-Good morning!
I couldn't take my eyes off Touko-chan.
Here you go, Yumi-sama.
Thanks, Noriko-chan.
Touko came to school today.
She looked as if nothing had happened during Christmas.
Yeah.
She did look like that.
You knew?
I met her unexpectedly earlier, right?
Yes.
Um... And then?
That's it.
We greeted each other and then separated.
Is that so...
It feels like she's hiding her true self more and more.
It would be nice if she opened herself up a bit more, though...
Anyway, let's end this conversation right now.
The tea will begin steeping.
Okay.
It's delicious.
Thank you very much.
Now then, I'll announce the plans for January.
Tomorrow after school,
there'll be a meeting regarding the election of next term's student council members,
so all second years must attend the meeting.
Noriko-chan, it's all right if you attend as well.
No, I'll pass.
It's all right if you run as a first year.
Yes. Just like what Shimako did last year.
If that happens, it'll be a battle between the White Rose sisters!
That'd be amazing to see!
Then Yoshino-san, Yumi-san and I
will just have to go to the election committee's office tomorrow after school, correct?
Yes.
With the formation of a new student council, Onee-sama will finally graduate...
The next day,
the meeting for the election of next semester's student council was held.
Please do your best in the election!
We're cheering for you three!
Ah, thank you.
Those of you who will be attending the meeting, please come in.
All right.
Sorry. Could you please let us through?
Touko.
There's something I want to talk to you about.
Sorry, but can you leave it until tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
I'm in a hurry right now.
Okay. Tomorrow it is.
Tomorrow, you're not going to skip school, right?
I'll be here.
You're quite distrustful of others.
Now then, since the deadline has past,
you three will be the only candidates.
In the end, there won't be any changes at the Rose Mansion because it's only us three here.
Yes.
Yeah.
Now then, please look at the print out.
First, we'll explain what's written on the page,
as well as some announcements from us.
The deadline has already passed!
Can you take care of it?
Yes.
What's wrong?
Sorry, but the deadline has already passed.
What's the matter?
There's one more person that would like to become a candidate.
Is that so? Hm...
Hanae-san!
Is there any way you can allow that person to participate?
If all of you are fine with it...
Let her in.
All right.
Please.
Touko-chan!
Good afternoon. Please excuse me.
Now, we'll resume the meeting.
Please take a look at the handouts in front of you.
We'll explain the contents of the sheets, as well as make some announcements.
Touko-chan...
Why?
Touko is running?
She never told me anything about it!
I was surpised as well.
Yumi-san, are you okay?
Your form is splendidly blank.
Y-Yeah...
Really! That Touko!
What is she thinking?
You're right. We should calm down
and think about what Touko is thinking.
Noriko-chan, what do you think?
I want to know what you think, as her friend.
Whether it's harassment or insinuation...
Both of them are bad, but I think it has to do with her attention towards Yumi-sama.
It's because I presented my rosary to her.
Yumi-san, don't think of that as a mistake!
Plus, elections are fair.
Touko-chan shouldn't be interested in becoming a serious candidate, so...
We don't know that for sure!
If Touko-chan is elected, it means that one of us won't be!
Shimako-san, are you saying that you'll forgive her for that?
But it's not our right to be elected.
I'm not saying if it's our right or not!
I just don't want to be separated from the friends that I love!
Yes, I understand what you're trying to say.
I'm certainly self-centered.
Even then, I don't care!
But, you know...
Aren't the things important to us obvious just from the words we speak so emotionally?
Not everyone can say things out of consideration for others like you can!
Yoshino-san, that's what I like about you.
Shimako-san, what are you...
From now on, please tell us your opinions straightforwardly.
U-Uh... Okay.
It'd become lonely if the three of them were to stop getting along.
It really would.
They'd become a good group of Roses, though.
Noriko-chan?
Hm?
Is there anything else we should be aware of about Touko-chan?
Nothing in particular...
Ah! I heard that she wanted to become a Rose from our classmates.
A Rose?
If so, she didn't have to turn down Yumi-san.
Yoshino.
But if she hadn't, she would've become someone close to Rosa Chinensis!
Then why did she turn her down?
Maybe she would hate it if she became my sister?
Touko doesn't hate you, Yumi-sama!
She's right. Touko-chan might have her own reasons for doing this.
We'll just have to wait and see for a bit.
Okay.
Why did Touko-chan become a candidate?
Did she want to become a Rose that much?
Or is she unsatisfied about the current student council for some reason?
If I'm a candidate, I'll have to compete with Touko-chan...
Have you heard?
That story about first year Matsudaira Touko-san from the Camellia class.
Surprising, right?
Isn't it troublesome for the Roses?
It must be.
Matsudaira-san, you're a candidate in the election for the student council?
Is there some sort of problem?
Why?
"Why?"
A lot of things have happened from Christmas until now, but isn't this all for one reason?
Noriko-san, you say difficult things sometimes, so I don't understand!
Stop playing around.
All right.
But even if what you're saying is true, is the answer something I have to tell you?
Just because we're friends, does that mean I have to tell you everything?
You're right.
I'm leaving.
Candidates have to hand in a report during lunch.
Touko.
I like you. I'm always thinking that I want to be your ally.
But, at the election, that's the one thing I can't be.
I honestly wish from my heart that my Onee-sama is elected to the student council.
That's why I'll be cheering her on.
That natural, isn't it?
I was happy that you called me a friend.
You're a good person, aren't you?
Not as good of one as you think I am.
What're you looking so gloomy over?
You can tell?
You think you can trick the of eyes of someone like me, who's been following you around since our first year?
I don't get Touko-chan at all.
Even I don't get that girl.
After all, she wears a mask the majority of the time, right?
A mask?
You haven't felt it?
I have.
You know, I think one good thing about you is that you always show an honest face.
You're bad at acting, aren't you?
I love that about you.
But do you think an amateur like you can win when you're standing on the same stage as that grand actress?
Then you mean...
No matter how hard I try to understand her, it's impossible for me?
If things continue like this.
There's no way you can win if you're unguardedly honest when your opponent is wearing a mask!
Oh! When I mean win, I don't mean the election.
Yeah.
Thanks for your advice.
Instead of your thanks...
Let me take a picture!
Come on.
This way!
Got it?
Make sure you get a good look inside the classroom while we're talking lively to each other.
This is Touko-chan's...
First look. We'll talk after.
And Rei-chan was really mean!
Before I got to say anything, she immediately started talking.
It was my first competition on a bike!
She said she'd look after me...
But ten years ago, I was riding properly with training wheels...
How was it?
What do you mean?
Normal? Is she the same as usual?
Or is she acting weird?
Even though we're in the middle of the election...
Yumi-sama? Yoshino-sama?
Speaking of which, there's no atmosphere of support for Touko in our class...
Right? Normally they would be supportive.
Does that...
Touko's at fault too.
When she's asked about the election, she ignores them, or leaves.
If she does that, she won't receive any support.
Yeah.
I wonder if Touko-chan's all right?
Um...
If it's fine with you, I can be your guide.
Oh, you're a life saver.
Actually, I came to deliver something my daughter forgot, but I don't know where she is.
Which class is your daughter in?
First year-
Ah, nevermind. Can you take me to the main office?
I'm sorry?
Would you like it if your mother came to deliver something you forgot?
Especially in front of your friends.
I completely understand!
Election for members of the student council.
Are you aware of the election?
Yes. I heard from my daughter.
This year the current Rosa Gigantea, Rosa Foetida en bouton, and Rosa Chinensis en bouton are candidates, aren't they?
It seems like my daughter's cheering them on as well.
She said, "They're all wonderful, so they'll definitely win!"
Wonderful, isn't it?
Touko.
Do you have a moment?
What's with those?
Did someone hide your shoes?
You're mistaken. I left my indoor shoes at home.
Why did you take them home then?
Just what I expected from you.
The reason I had to take them home was because they were dirtied to the point where I had to wash them.
That's terrible.
Who would do something like that?
It's nothing big.
Why are you smiling?
I'm not smiling.
You're smiling.
As if you're enjoying this situation.
Noriko-san, you're reading too deep into this.
Let's go to the office. I'll go with you.
Don't tell me, you're going to tell the teachers?
I'm not. The teacher asked for you.
Your mother dropped this off for you.
My mother?
She said she noticed you left these in the doorway.
What a nice mother.
Yes.
She is.
And then, no matter if we were laughing or crying, the day of the election arrived.
I'm relieved.
I didn't know if you were going to drop out, so I was really nervous inside.
I thought about doing so the entire time, but...
Do you mind if I ask why you didn't?
I had the chance to talk to a student's mother who came to our school a few days ago.
Her daughter had told her that she was supporting us.
Up until now, I've worried about Touko-chan all on my own,
but I shouldn't forget the people that are supporting us, right?
I arrived at the conclusion that I couldn't give up, and now I'm here.
That's it!
It'd be great if you can give a speech the way you talked just now!
Your expression and the way you talked were fantastic!
Onee-sama!
We will now begin with the speeches from the candidates seeking election to next year's student council.
What happened to Rei-chan?
Sorry!
Jeez, you're late!
Onee-sama, please do your best!
I'm cheering you on! You'll definitely be fine!
And...
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Noriko...
Onee-sama...
You're shaking.
I was shaking too, back then.
Got it? It's all right to be nervous.
There's absolutely no need for you to show people someone who isn't you.
Show everyone in the hall who you really are.
Go with that in mind.
Onee-sama, I have a request.
All right.
Please hug me.
Like this?
I could feel Onee-sama's warmth.
"The role of an older sister is to embrace and protect."
Those words came back to mind.
I am not unsatisfied with the current Yamayuri Council, nor the Roses themselves.
However, that doesn't mean that the wind of change is unnecessary.
Touko-chan gave a spectacular performance.
Boldly, she was able to thoroughly show her conviction.
Shimako-san said she would be able to fulfill her promises in her own way.
And Yoshino-san also fascinated everyone that listened to her.
I need to present myself honestly too.
And lastly, Fukuzawa Yumi-san.
Please give us your speech.
Yes!
Elections and becoming sisters are similar in a way.
Even now, I still want to make Touko-chan my sister.
But Touko-chan should choose the path she believes in.
I don't even have to know what that path is, as long as Touko-chan's happy.
Good afternoon.
My name is Fukuzawa Yumi.
Everyone did what they could.
No regrets.
Touko-chan...
Here it comes, Yumi-san.
Yeah...
We will now be presenting the results of the election for the members of next year's student council.
Next year's student council members will be...
these three!
Yumi-san!
Congratulations, Yumi.
Touko-chan...
Touko-chan didn't enter the election out of spite.
Neither was it because she wanted to become a Rose.
Yumi-sama.
I saw Touko's face the moment the results were released.
And then...
And then I knew.
Touko's purpose was to lose!
I knew it!
Touko-chan!
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
Really, Noriko-chan, your support had a lot of spirit!
Huh?
"Please honestly try your best! You'll be fine! I believe in you!"
And then, "Fight"?
There's no way Shimako-san wouldn't power up after that.
Eh? Is that true?
Of course!
Shimako-san's soft smile returned.
Next time: Key holder.
I hope Touko can also receive energy and a smile from Yumi-sama.