-ED-
白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
Don't leave me...
It'll be okay, mama.
Don't go anywhere.
Don't leave me behind.
So please...
I won't. I'm here.
Where did you go, my baby?
Papa, welcome home.
You're still awake?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
I was just by mama's side.
It seemed like she was having a hard time sleeping.
Is that so?
Sorry for being late.
Papa...
Hm?
Maybe it's my fault?
It's not!
Because of that, you're always needlessly holding yourself back, aren't you?
You're getting the wrong impression, papa.
I haven't thought of it like that even once.
What happened on that day was a shock for her.
If you hadn't been affected emotionally by the event, mama and I may never have noticed the screams coming from your heart.
It must have been an incredibly heavy load for a sixteen year old to carry alone.
As parents, that's something we must bear the responsibility for.
That's why I agree with grandfather's decision.
You should paint your life on a pure white canvas freely without having to worry about who you are.
You can't just give and take in this world.
I'll just take what I can.
There's nothing I can give in return.
Mama, grandfather, and I have already received plenty from you.
Ah, Touko-chan!
Good day.
I apologize for my absence until now.
Too bad about the election.
It's nothing.
President, I've come today to pick up the form for quitting the club.
What're you saying?!
So...
Does this have anything to do with your loss in the election?
No.
I have personal reasons.
I thought this day might come.
If I retire from the club because of exams,
you might be ostracized by other members.
You know...
I want you to serve as the face of the Drama club from now on.
It doesn't matter how.
Stay in the club.
The other members can learn a lot of things from you when it comes to acting.
If you can't get along with the older members, I have an idea.
Become my sister.
If you become the club president's sister, you won't be attacked anymore, right?
Even next year, becoming my sister won't lose its effect that easily.
But, I...
Fukuzawa Yumi-san?
I understand you.
You like her, don't you?
I've been looking at you this entire time, after all.
I thought it would be fine if you can be happy by becoming Yumi-san's sister.
But you've come back here, hurt, while trying to get closer to her.
There must be something wrong with me.
You're right.
If you don't change, you won't be able to walk with Yumi-san together.
So in order for you to distance yourself from the Yamayuri Council and the Rose Mansion,
you ran in an election you knew you would lose, didn't you?
It hurts to see you suffer.
Forget about Yumi-san already.
I'll protect you.
I'm sorry...
I cannot choose the club president in order to separate myself from Yumi-sama.
Touko.
What's with you?
I'm lying in an ambush.
So I don't stand out, of course.
What do you want?
There's something I want to ask about.
It's about what happened at Christmas.
Why did you say something like that to Yumi-chan?
Something like that?
I don't understand your feelings, even though I know you like Yumi-chan.
Who did you hear that from?
I can tell just by looking.
You're not very persuasive.
Then let me ask you this.
Why didn't you go to Canada last summer?
When you heard that Yumi-chan was going to the Ogasawara's villa,
you changed your plans, didn't you?
T-That's...
At the time, I thought you decided to go to the villa in order to interfere with the two of them because you were jealous.
But that wasn't it.
Touko, you were worried about Yumi-chan.
What're you...
You knew those girls were dangerous.
So what if I did go to the villa?
Even then, you didn't go to a foreign country that would take you far away from her.
I get it.
You were afraid that the bullying you received would happen to Yumi-chan as well.
Exactly who did it and when did they do it?
Was it Kyougoku? Ayanokouji? Saionji?!
Onii-sama...
I never noticed.
Up until the moment you ran away from home, I had believed that you didn't know anything!
Onii-sama?
Onii-sama!
I have to pee!
You saved me just now.
If you hadn't made me stop, it would've been dangerous.
You saved me too.
Since we made it on time to the bathroom.
Onii-sama, I wasn't that shocked by it.
I've already detached myself from it.
So you don't have to become that angry.
Touko...
It's okay if you become happy.
What're you talking about?
You're running away from the happiness in front of you.
You adore Yumi-chan.
That's in the past!
Are you telling me that I should have accepted her rosary that time, then?!
Yumi-chan chose you as her sister?
Why are you so surprised after all that's happened?
I didn't know.
I don't know anything specific about what's happened between you and Yumi-chan.
That's why I tricked you into telling me.
Don't tell such an obvious lie!
Why do you doubt me so much?
If I'm going to trust and then be betrayed, I'd rather not trust in the first place!
Wrong.
Although you say you don't trust others, deep down inside you do want to trust.
While you run away, you wait for someone to chase after you.
That's not-
If you keep running away like that, no one's going to chase after you.
Why is everyone attacking me?
It must be because everyone likes you.
Attacked because I'm liked? I don't get it.
The world's filled with things that can't be understood.
So you waited in ambush to ask me that?
Why did you go this far?
I just wanted to know.
About what happened between you and Yumi-chan.
Why did you want to know?
If you think about it, you'll understand.
If I think about it...
Treasure hunting?
Exactly one year ago, during last year's treasure hunt,
Ah, over there!
I saw her for the first time.
Lively.
Straightforward.
This was the person that Sachiko onee-sama had chosen.
I thought she was scary.
I don't know the reason.
It was just a vague feeling...
...of fear.
Even so...
Before I knew it, I...
Touko-chan!
I'm stupid.
I'm stupid!
Well then, good day everyone.
Good day to you too!
Touko!
You seem busy.
Are you heading towards the Rosa Mansion?
Nope, today I'm taking a break.
I'm in a hurry because they're doing a special on Buddha statues on T.V.!
I see.
Anyway, good day.
Noriko-san!
Yes?
Um...
It must be tough! You're hiding your card this year, right?
Nope.
The three second years are hiding their treasure.
If I remember, there's...
Do you have this?
No...
Then it's yours.
I've already read it, and I can see it at the Rosa Mansion at any time.
See you then.
The three second years are hiding their treasure.
Oh?
Good day.
G-Good day.
Are you heading home?
Yes.
Then let's walk together until the station.
Did you need me for something?
Did I?
It's like first calling out to a friend to stop them.
And then wondering why I did it.
Do you understand?
Yes...
Touko-chan.
Sorry for being unreasonable.
I wasn't thinking.
Before thinking about it, I offered you my rosary.
Without actually thinking about your feelings,
I got ahead of myself thinking about my own feelings.
I think it's obvious that you'd be shocked at me.
That was my apology.
And now this is a suggestion,
can we return our relationship to how it was before Christmas?
I don't understand what's inside your heart, Yumi-sama!
Why are you being so tolerant to an underclassman that refused your rosary?!
Why did you think of making someone like me your sister in the first place?
Can you stop saying self-depreciating things like "people like me"?
For people like me...
"People like me" fits!
I've already decided that...
what you did was due to your own confusion.
I've accepted that.
Even then, why do you still bother with me?
You don't know?
You know,
I've been thinking ever since I was refused by you.
"How will things go between us?"
But I should have thought about what I wanted to do.
After that, I understood.
I'm perfectly fine if you can be yourself.
"Me being myself," you said?
That's right.
So no matter what you do, I won't falter with my feelings.
Even when it came to your reason for running in the election.
I didn't dig for it when you didn't tell me your reason.
It's also the same when you ran away from home.
What kind of people your parents are,
what your relationship with them is like now,
or what kind of childhood you had.
Those things are of an entirely different dimension than the feeling of embracing you.
Is that so?
Is that how it was?
What happened that time was, in the end, just your pity for me, wasn't it?
You just wanted to be charitable on the Holy Night!
When you handed that rosary to me, it must've felt good, didn't it?
If I can be myself?
It has nothing to do with my parents?
I thought it was strange!
There's no way you could wish for me to be your sister!
But now I've finally solved the mystery!
What're you talking about?
If you did it unconsciously, then it's even worse!
Aren't you misunderstanding something?
Don't come toward me!
Don't get any closer to me than that!
Touko-chan...
I don't want to hear any excuses!
I understand.
No matter what I say now, it seems like you won't listen.
Touko-chan.
Count to one hundred from where you are.
Don't move before you've finished counting.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen, fifteen, sixteen...
Forty-seven, forty-eight, forty-nine, fifty...
Ninety-five, ninety-six, ninety-seven, ninety-eight, ninety-nine, one hundred.
Excuse me!
Is something wrong?
Did you say anything to Yumi-sama?!
About what?
Well...
Tell me clearly!
It seems like you've come to me to complain about something,
but if you don't say it clearly, I won't understand.
It's about my birth!
Your birth?
You remember it, don't you?
So? When did you tell her?!
Like I said, what're you-
Please don't play dumb!
I'm talking about the fact that I'm not the Matsudairas' daughter!
Touko-chan, you aren't the daughter Mr. Matsudaira and Mrs. Matsudaira gave birth to?
Could it be...
Unfortunately, this is my first time hearing this.
That's a lie.
It's the truth.
No way...
Then someone must've told her...
Suguru onii-sama?
No, he didn't look like he had said anything.
Really, you've been patronizing.
I'm sorry!
Not to me.
I'm talking about Yumi.
I'm sure Yumi has no idea about your family circumstances!
Even if she found out on accident, she's not the type of girl who would change how she sees you!
I know this the best because I'm her older sister.
Although, I've started to pity Yumi, who only thinks about you.
Then everything was my...
misunderstanding...
Yumi-sama...
I don't know what I should do anymore...
Count to one hundred from where you are.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
I'm now alone.
...eight, nine...
I cut my bonds that
...ten, eleven...
I had been connected to
one by one.
...twelve, thirteen...
Thirty-one, thirty-two, thirty-three...
But I was lonely.
...thirty-four, thirty-five, thirty-six...
It didn't matter who. I wanted them by my side.
If you keep running away like that, no one's going to chase after you.
Fifty-six, fifty-seven...
I'm afraid of counting on!
...fifty-eight, fifty-nine...
I'm afraid of opening my eyes, and finding myself all alone!
Seventy-five, seventy-six, seventy-seven, seventy-eight, seventy-nine, eighty, eighty-one...
Oh, sorry. I was thinking I probably shouldn't interrupt, but...
Why?
Didn't you go home?
After leaving, I felt a bit worried about you.
But the special...
You're more important.
Noriko!
What happened exactly?
Maria-sama, thank you very much!
Thank you for returning Noriko.
Noriko...
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
Today's Valentine's Day.
I ended up receiving chocolate from Mami-san and her sister from the newspaper club!
Wha- Chocolate from me?
Mami-san, you should say "Thank you" first, shouldn't you?
That "first" is unnecessary, isn't it?
And after that, "I'm very happy!"
I-I'm very happy!
But I'm the demon of Lilian's newspaper club!
Just because it's Valentine's Day doesn't mean all you do is be joyful!
Next time: Crisscross.
How'll this year's treasure hunt go?
Who'll be searching for our cards?