-ED-
白い傷大きく広げ
Shiroi kizu ookiku hiroge
Open up your pale wounds,
宝箱隠しにいこう
Takarabako kakushi ni ikou
And let's go hide the treasure chest.
コートなんていらない ご霜で
Koto nante iranai goshimo de
I don't need a coat, even in the frost.
シャーペンの芯だけはいて
Shaapen no shin dake haite
I'll just take my pencil lead.
くるるくるるく　かけぬける
Kururu kururu ku kakenukeru
Kururu kururu ku, let's run past it.
くるるくるるく　足跡は罰印だよ
Kururu kururu ku ashiato wa batsujirushi dayo
Kururu kururu ku, these footprints are the proof of our punishment.
校舎の壁突き抜け
Kousha no kabe tsukinuke
Break through the school walls,
どこにもいける　そこに道がある
doko ni mo ikeru soko ni michi ga aru
and we can go anywhere on the paths out there.
スカートのひだ乱れない
sukato no hida midarenai
The pleats on my skirt won't get messed up,
秘密の旅なら
Himitsu no tabi nara
as long as it's a secret journey.
Then everything was my...
misunderstanding...
Yumi-sama...
I don't know what I should do anymore...
Count to one hundred from where you are.
One, two, three,
four, five, six...
Seventy-five, seventy-six, seventy-seven, seventy-eight...
Seventy-nine, eighty...
eighty one...
Oh, sorry. I was thinking I probably shouldn't interrupt, but...
Noriko!
Noriko...
After that, without having told me anything,
Touko and I parted at the station.
Good morning.
Good morning, Touko.
Touko, are you participating in the treasure hunt?
It's not something you should be worried about.
At the beginning of the week, Touko returned back to normal.
Just what exactly is she thinking?
Good afternoon, Onee-sama!
Good afternoon, Yumi.
Um...
Wait.
Let's change location.
Yumi, you might not have noticed yet, but...
my classmates were peeking at us with full interest.
But seeing us together shouldn't be that rare of a thing anymore.
They knew that last year, I was excited when I received chocolate,
but I only accepted yours.
They were curious how I would look when-
Please allow me to be the only one who knows how you look when you receive chocolate.
It feels like you're demanding it.
Not at all!
Thanks.
Oh!
These are...
Surprising chocolates?
No. Level two!
There's so much love in them it'll surprise you!
Then...
These are from me, okay?
Could these be chocolates?!
Last year, when you gave me chocolate, I was extremely happy.
So this year, I wanted to convey my feelings with these.
Onee-sama.
Thank you very much!
Am I the only one receiving these?
Yes, they're only for you.
For now, I want put a little distance between Touko-chan and myself.
I see...
It seems like there was some kind of misunderstanding though...
I've decided to wait until Touko-chan decides to talk to me again.
It really is a shame.
These are filled with so much love.
E-Excuse me!
Sorry!
What're you apologizing for?
That's because, you were about to receive chocolate, weren't you?
I was, but it's not something I wouldn't want others to see.
Yumi-sama's reaction just now was like
a middle school boy who walked in when girls were changing, wasn't it?
No, what I saw just now was worse than seeing girls change in a way...
The White Rose sisters.
It's like they're in their own world.
Then that means...
From other people's view, the way Onee-sama and I looked just now was...
Jeez! That's so embarrassing!
Oh no, no, no!
It's really...
quite interesting watching Yumi-san, isn't it?
Yes.
You're late!
Sorry!
Of course, both the White Rose and the Red Rose families...
enjoyed giving and receiving chocolate today!
You guys must've been really busy!
But unfortunately, the head of the Yellow Rose family has exams so she's absent!
Rei-sama isn't coming?
Who knows?
She said something along the lines of coming after her exam is over,
but I wonder if she will!
So, since everyone's gathered together,
let's start our final conference for the treasure hunt!
Today's the day of the event, after all!
Are you running away?
I'm talking about today's treasure hunt.
Are you going to show up or not?
I don't understand what you mean.
Even if I don't go,
I don't believe there's any reason for it to be called "running away."
Is that so?
From my eyes, it looks like you're running away from Yumi.
Are you afraid of facing her?
You're afraid, aren't you?
I'm afraid too.
It's because she's too honest.
She doesn't do this on purpose...
But when she's with you,
it feels like your weaknesses are being poked at.
It's as if your self is being reflected back by an undistorted, unclouded mirror.
I don't want to see it.
I don't want to accept it.
Even I've thought that...
Then why are you two still together?
Isn't it obvious?
It's because I love her.
It certainly is difficult having your weaknesses prodded at,
but more importantly, it's more painful not being together with her.
You know, I've started to think that if there are parts of me that I don't like,
then it'll be good if I change those aspects
while I'm being reflected in the mirror that Yumi is.
Why are you telling me this now?
I'm already...
I've prepared myself for the one day that Yumi will find a younger sister.
I wonder, what kind of younger sister she'll be.
It's both fun and lonely thinking about what that girl will be like.
But Yumi can't be mistaken about who she chooses as her sister.
That's what I believed, and that's what I want to believe even now.
But you won't become my rival.
I thought that the only person that would be able to be my rival at the treasure hunt would be you,
but there's nothing I can do if you aren't willing to stand at the start line.
Please wait!
Oh?
There's quite a lot of people who have gathered.
Ah! Sachiko-sama's there too!
Yumi-san, your fans are closing in around her little by little.
That person!
What a surprise!
Touko-chan came!
Touko...
We will now begin the treasure hunt for the next Roses' treasure!
Red, white, and yellow.
These cards are hidden separately within the area contained by the lines drawn on the maps provided.
The individuals who find a card
will receive the right to have a date for half a day with one of the next Roses.
If a card isn't found before the 4:40 time limit,
we'll be giving a chance to the others...
who couldn't make it, and thus placed a guess of the locations in the box beforehand.
For that reason, Nijo Noriko has declined to participate in the event itself,
and instead will be working as staff.
Rosa Foetida, Hasekura Rei-sama, submitted her guess several days ago.
Rosa Chinensis, who will be participating,
will be handicapped by waiting five minutes before starting her search.
This year, there are hints in different places as well,
so please do your best to find the cards!
So then, let's start!
Oh!
You girls...
None of you have to accompany me during my handicap.
Are we bothering you?
Not at all.
That's right!
How about having tea together, everyone?
Hey, hey, isn't that a hint?
White roses...
What does "ku" mean?
Apparently there's a total of nine characters for Shimako-sama's card hint.
There was a "ma" character stuck on the board of the student council room.
Really!
Where is it?
Did you find it?
They're at it!
The hint for the white card is "Ta-ku-ma-shi-no?"
It's not just in hiragana; there was a illustration of a bunny too, wasn't there?
I wonder what that means...
I found another hint!
I wonder if anyone's found Yoshino's card yet?
I pray that,
no one finds her card,
and the right to have a date with her is given to me, who sent in a guess.
That's... It can't be...
Yoshino put that there?
Rei-sama!
Did you finish with your exam today?
May I have one more cup?
Ah, sure!
Thank you.
Why has Sachiko-sama been drinking tea in this room this entire time
instead of searching for your card?
I don't know...
Rosa Chinensis, do you already have an idea of where Yumi-sama's card is?
Not at all.
Then does that mean you've given up searching for it?
They're both wrong.
I am participating in this event because I want to find Yumi's card.
But I can't find it if I just go around searching blindly, can I?
That's why I'm here, waiting for now.
What're you waiting for?
For Rosa Chinensis en bouton to let something slip.
Excuse me,
but is it all right if I leave for a moment?
You're concerned about her, aren't you?
Go ahead.
When I was in primary school, they gave us new blank maps in social studies.
At the time, I was very happy.
Unfortunately, it's not there.
Apparently it isn't.
Blank maps?
Was there an episode between you and Yumi-sama related to blank maps?
Did you think that Yumi-sama would want you to find the card,
so she would've put it in a place only the two of you would think of?
Is that what you thought?
Are you going to laugh at my conceit?
That's not it!
You're treating Yumi-sama too lightly!
Yumi-sama thinks of you preciously,
but she's not someone that can only look at you!
I knew it.
I knew that Touko now,
would be in this small room,
searching for Yumi-sama!
But no matter how much you search,
Yumi-sama isn't in a place like this!
Yumi-sama has always been bigger than you thought.
So big that she can't enter this room.
That's why you can't see her.
That's why you don't understand her, Touko!
That time...
You were trying to break out of this narrow, suffocating situation!
That's what I thought. Am I wrong?!
If you're always smoldering on your own in a cramp place,
you won't be able to reach Yumi-sama!
This way, you'll never be able to find Yumi-sama's card!
Have you said whatever you wanted to say?
Since we're friends, I have to say things that need to be said.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Was it cold? Your nose is red.
No, I'm fine.
I see.
What about the cards?
None of them have been found yet.
I'm sticking with just a second serving.
Yumi-sama, do you think the red card will be found?
Who knows...
Has someone finally found a card?
Yoshino.
Rei-chan!
What happened?
Nothing much.
I just brought this.
What?!
Rei-chan, you idiot!
You idiot!
Yoshino, you don't have to fire off so many "idiots"...
What's wrong with calling an idiot an idiot?
Show everyone what you've brought!
Please excuse me...
Valentine's Day Chocolate request order form?!
What?!
If I get into the college,
I figured the first thing I'd do is make Yoshino a cake.
If I'm going to make a cake,
I might as well take requests and make an amazing one!
An examinee like you shouldn't think about these things!
But bringing a yellow piece of paper like this...
made us think that it was a card from the event.
Oh, I found the card.
But it'd be bad if someone without the right to take it, took it, right?
I pretended I didn't see it.
Hi!
Chisato-san!
Why did you come here?
Oh? I can't be here?
I have a good reason for being here.
Reason?
Yep!
I have the yellow card here with me!
Why did Sachiko-sama choose that person to be her sister?
You're too happy.
I hate the part of you that's so optimistic!
Let's go to the Drama club right now!
I'll go with you!
You're making such an unguarded expression again.
Touko-chan.
Touko-chan!
Touko-chan...
Will you become my sister?
If this is charity for this holy night,
please take it somewhere else!
It's because she's too honest.
When she's with you,
it feels like your weaknesses are being poked at.
Then why are you two still together?
Isn't it obvious?
It's because I love her.
Because... she loves her.
Because she loves her.
The yellow card was found by Chisato-san for the second year in a row.
The white and red cards have yet to be found.
Who will find my card, I wonder?
Onee-sama?
Or maybe...
Yumi.
Y-Yes?
Yumi-sama!
machi no irodori sae doko to naku sabishige na fuyu no keshiki
Somehow, despite the colors of the city, the lonely winter scenery
senaka misekakete ita anata wo omou
makes me think of when you showed your back to me.
futari no aida ni wa toumei na shikakkei
Between the two of us is a transparent wall
ima wa kasunderu tameiki no kesshou de
which is turning foggy with my crystallized sighs.
mado garasu mado garasu kumotteta anata ja mienai wa
Window glass, window glass, so obscure that I cannot see you,
soko ni iru koto wa wakatte iru noni
even though I know that you're right there.
waratteru naiteru no shika nai tsura demo ii kara misete
Whether you're laughing, or crying, show me your face.
sochira no hou kara mo garasu wo muite
Look at the glass from your side too.
After the Valentine's Day plans,
I had a date with Tanuma Chisato.
It ended up being the same as the one she had with Rei-chan last year.
I ended up having a date with Iga Ami-san, who participated through the absentee guesses.
But that Ami-san wasn't the real one!
And that's enough of that story!
What kind of date will Yumi-san and Touko-chan have?
Next time: Searching for You.
Finally, I can reach Touko-chan.